[music]
[snorts]
All right, y'all. We are live on this
beautiful
Wednesday afternoon. God bless everybody
in Jesus name. I do pray you and your
family are super blessed, guys. And I
hope you know what I did before this
stream. I had to go wash my hands. I had
to wash my hands.
Because man, I'm I I'm getting chopped
up today, man. I'm feeling extra dirty.
I suck at trading, man. I'll be honest.
I totally suck at I'm the worst trader
in the world, man. I suck. I'm the
worst, man. But you know what? That's
okay, cuz it's FOMC today. We're going
to see if we can catch a juicy trade
during
FOMC. And we're going to see if the
Bitcoin price is going to dip, grip, or
rip. All right. Are we going to pump?
Are we going to dump? We're gonna have
to see. All right. Make sure to wash
your hands because things are about to
get dirty.
All right. Bitcoin is pumping
right now leading up to this FOMC. We
got to give a big shout to everyone in
the chat. First of all, shout out to Joe
Potter. Shout out to Investment Time.
Shout out to Flip Frank. Shout out to
the Null Paradox
in the chat. Shout out to James Quick
Business commercial as soon as I went
live. Well, you got to get the YouTube
premium, bro. I don't know what else to
tell you, man. Shout out to Prime Vids,
Trace, and Espanol, and shout out to
Splashfire Films. Am I long or short?
So, I'm in a short, guys. But here's the
thing. I was in a long trade. I got
wrecked. All right. Got wrecked. Lost
money on my long trade that I tried to
take from this
level right here. Okay. Took a long from
here, guys. Took a long from here.
would have been in profit if I had but I
got stopped out. Okay. Didn't take my
short trade that I was planning for this
morning. All right. So, this morning I
had planned to take a short trade from
here. Didn't take it. Wasn't at the
charts. Had a beautiful bearish
divergence and all that good stuff. All
right. Then I decided to take my long
trade and I got absolutely wrecked just
to get stop hunted. And now we're
pumping. And uh yeah, that's that's what
it's the deal. Am I long or short? Well,
I'm in a long still from the long from
June 25th. The same old swing trade,
$40,000 in profit. I'm in a short trade
right now. I've locked in. How much have
I locked in? Five grand or something.
Yeah, I've locked in five grand. I'm
probably going to get my stop loss hit,
you know. Let's see. I added to the
trade. Seeing maybe if if FOMC dumps us.
Let's see what FOMC is going to do. Man,
I'm excited today. I hope you guys are
just as excited as your boy Jason
Casperoni
because today is the federal funds rate.
In three minutes,
we are going to find out whether or not
they do anything. And right now, baked
into the cake, the forecast is that
they're going to do nothing. And right
now I've got butterflies in my stomach,
big old monarch, beautiful orange
butterflies
as I'm awaiting the news, which in which
volatility is going to ensue. And then
approximately 30 minutes later, our good
old friend Kevin Borch is going to come
out of the closet and start telling us
all about inflation.
All right. Is inflation going down or is
it going up? We're going to have to see.
All right. I hope he's ready to wash his
hands cuz he's about to get a little
dirty himself with all the weird strange
nonsense that's about to spew out of his
mouth. Look at how clean my hands are.
Guys, inspect your hands right now. Do
your hands look like Jason Casper's
hands? Do your hands look like Jason
Casper's hands? Look at Jason Casper's
hands. Your hands better look like my
hands. They're freshly washed. All
right, you can see that they've been
washed, these hands. All right, so make
sure to smash up the likes, guys. And
we're going to see. We are going to see
if we're going to get a move here. And
honestly, I'm just going to be totally
honest. Like, if we dump down to this
level right here, I'm going to have to
FOMO into a long trade. I might have to
lose it all here live on YouTube, man.
At this point, I might have to lose it
all live on YouTube. All right. So, I
have to wait and see what's going to
happen. We got three minutes. Tenuto
miss amigos.
The real King Solomon is in the bubble
bath for how dirty this is going to be.
Who's going to be number 68? Guys, smash
up the likes. We have 613 likes. I'm
sorry. 613 watchers. We need to get the
likes up to the watchers. You know, I'm
talking about the watchers from the book
of Enoch. We need to get the likes
smashed up to the watchers, baby.
Liberty and Trust says no change. Watch.
I don't have a watch. Actually, I do
have a watch. I don't know if you can
see. I got a watch
right there. It's like a tattoo of a
watch on my arm, but
it always has the same time.
Shout out to R. Pink. He says, "Trading
keeps you humble." That's for sure. One
day you feel like a fortune teller, next
not so much. That's true. You know, I
remember a few months ago I felt like
the best trader in the world. Now I
literally feel [__] Am I [__]
guys? I think the answer could be yes. I
think the answer could be yes. I mean,
let's be honest. [laughter]
I mean, when I look at myself, I
honestly question everything. I question
everything. But I'll tell you one thing
I don't question. That's making sure
that my hands are washed cuz we're
getting ready for the ultimate 1 minute
until insane volatility is about to pump
into the market, baby. Here we go. And
we're going to watch the press
conference live. We got 51 seconds. I
got bootterflies in meo.
Loser flies in meo.
Give me a right hike and dump it. Says
summit trades. Guys, did you wash your
hands today?
Yeah. Did you wash your hands today?
Jason Casper washed his hands. He washed
his hands. Um,
Jason Casper, watchers from Enoch, don't
care about Bitcoin. Well, at least
they're watching. I don't know. Can
Billy do a series on the Book of Enoch?
Oh, man. That would be crazy.
Shout out to Real Cipher Rider.
Hopefully, we got a pump song today,
man. You know, let's see, man.
Let's see. Let's see. All right. Here we
go, guys. 10 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1. Looks
like we're going for the pump first,
man. We're going for the pump first. All
right, here we go. Oh my goodness. Oh
my. Wow. There's Oh,
whoa. Whoa. Oh my goodness. WHAT THE
ACTUAL [laughter]
LOOK AT THAT. CRAZY. WHAT? What even
happened? No change. No change. Oh my
goodness.
Relax, Jason. Relax. Deep plunger
breathing.
Oh man. Wow. Would you look at that
Wiccaroni? That is crazy. Wow. That is
crazy, guys. Oh my goodness. That's
nuts. All right. Look at this. Wow. My
goodness.
Would you look at this, man? This is
crazy right now. Okay, so here's the
deal. I mean, we are getting a big move
right now based on the news.
And there is a chance, honestly, that if
we take the highs, we get a little bit
of a pullback here. Let's see what
happens. Are we even going to take the
high? Let's see what happens. This is
some insane price action. You literally
have seen me lose $2,000 in a matter of
seconds on this. We got alerts popping
out the wazoo right now. Bitcoin is
crossing 64.3.
Man, if only my long trade didn't get
stopped out, I would have been in. That
was my take profit. That was gonna be my
take profit on there. But you know what?
That's just how the market moves. That's
what I get for trading FOMC before FOMC.
That's what I get, man. You know what I
mean? That's what I get. No change for
you. No change, guys. Wash your hands
cuz our clothes are not getting washed
or changed. All right. Our clothes are
not getting washed or changed. It's
going to be a nothing burger. I feel
craziness coming, says James. Quick
Business. You need to clean out your
garage cuz you know I'm cleaning out the
garage. You know what I'm doing right
now? Actually, I'm putting together I'm
putting together in the garage, guys.
This this uh it's a uh what is it? What
What is it? It's a
forget. It's like a keppy a keppy 6000
bench, right? It's like a bench. It's
like the best bench I ever had. I have
one of these benches in Cuba. I have a
bench in Cuba
in my villa in Cuba. I have the Keepy
6000. So, I decided to get one for the
homestead back in the United States cuz
I've been using a really cheap,
dangerous incline bench. And this
morning, not this morning, the last time
I worked out, that thing nearly almost
fell apart on me.
Oh man, I highly recommend the Keepy
6000 if you're looking for an
incline/deline/fat
flat bench. This bench does it all. Does
it all. You can even do Nordic curls on
it. Does it all. All right, let's see.
Are we about to get wrecked and stopped
out of this short trade? What is about
to happen here,
man? Oh man. Oh man. Oh man. Oh man. Oh
man. Oh man. Oh man. Oh man. Oh man. Oh
man. Oh man. Oh man. Rates held. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Here we go. Incoming candle.
Yeah. Let's see what's going to happen
here. Let's take a look at the order
flow while we wait. while we wait for
our good friend Walsh.
What has happened here? Let's check it.
So, basically, guys, just longs opening
up. $1 billion in this one candle here.
$1 billion candle volume. What an insane
increase in volume. And that is actual
longs coming in right now, guys. That is
actual longs coming in right now. Wow.
In 1 minute, guys. 100 million longs
popping in. 800 million volume in 1
minute,
man. If we if we if we look come below
these guys, we will have 100 million
longs. And
can you imagine that? Can you imagine
that? This is about to get insane during
this press conference. You know what I'm
saying?
You can do bicep curls on any bench,
man. This bench, I'll tell you, it has
it the it has better bicep curl
attachments because it has it has these
little attachments that go on and you
could you could really get the stretch
the stretch in the bicep, man. You could
really get that stretch in the bicep.
You know what I'm saying? The stretch in
the bicep. Do I think longs will get
trapped? I hope they get trapped. I hope
the longs get trapped because I want to
long from lower. I want to wreck these
longs,
you know? I want to wreck them, baby.
Let's let's take a look at the dang
Bitcoin chart here and see what's going
on. All right, we're going to start on
our daily time frame while we wait for
this press conference here. All right,
let's just close off everything right
now. We're going to remove everything.
Here's the deal, man.
Here is the deal. Right now,
what I'm really hoping, what I was
actually really hoping for was that the
Bitcoin price would come down just a
little bit lower to this area where we
have a Fibonacci golden pocket.
Nah, that's not the golden pocket I was
looking at.
What golden pocket was I looking at?
Now, now, now I don't even know what the
heck I'm talking about anymore. Let's go
back to my actual chart. All right,
Fibonacci golden pocket from the local
low that we put in on Tuesday the 28th
of July, which was yesterday to the
current high. And we have all this
liquidity down here. This is where I
wanted. All right, this is where I
wanted the long trade from. All right,
this is where I want the long trade
from. I want to wreck everybody here and
we would have a juicy bullish dip if we
can manage to come down there. Let's
come down there now. Come on, baby. Come
on, Kevin. Come on, Kevin. Jason Casper
needs a fresh long trade. Come on,
Kevin. Let's come on down there. Let's
inspect how would things look if we came
down there. I mean, you know, the
reality of the situation is they would
look pretty dang bullish. Like, let's
take a look at market cipher B on the 1
hour.
Man, we come down there.
Yeah, actually 1 hour wouldn't look that
great. 24m minute would actually look
pretty nice. 24m minute would actually
look pretty nice if we made our way down
there because the 24m minute if we go
ahead and we put this on
we would now be able to form a local
uneven butt cheek and our 12minut time
frame would have a nice uneven butt
cheek there. Yeah, if we come down there
things would be looking pretty nice.
Let's see.
Let's see. Let's see. We squeeze all
these shorts. Let's see. Let's see. All
right.
I'm short. Make me a short king. Kevin
Walsh. Come on, Kevin Walsh. Gonna wash
out the whole market. I can't wait to
wash my hands, man. I'm feeling good
right now. Come on, Kevin Walsh. Don't
make us feel like this. Go from this to
this. Look at that. Look at the change.
Look at the forehead wrinkles. My
goodness. Just two weeks, two months as
the fed chair. And you can literally go
from this to this. From this to a happy
young go-lucky guy to this.
That's tough. That's tough. That's
tough. Look at those hands. Those are
some tough hands, man. Those are some
tough hands, baby.
I know. At least just take the low from
yesterday. Sheesh. That's what I'm
looking for. That's what I'm looking
for.
I'm going to be happy if it does to 62
today. Now 62, that would be even
juicier.
62 would be even juicier. But you know
what? I am a little interested in a long
from 62. I'm more interested in a long
from 60k. I'm not going to lie. Like in
general,
the place I would really like, and I'm
not saying we're going to come down
there, but it would really be to take
out all of this here, right? This is
really the long that I've been lusting
after. This one right here, right? Come
on down.
My soul lustth after this. I'm telling
you, it it that would be really nice. We
would have bullish divergence out the
wazoo. We'd have a beautiful back test
of the good oldfashioned value area low
of the range. Bam. Now, that that's what
I'm talking about, baby. But we've been
chopping around this PC,
you know, between you and me. We've just
been chopping around this PC to figure
out what's it going to be. You know, we
spent the last how many days chip
chopping around chip chopity.
We got ourselves about 22 minutes until
Jerome Powell's uh not predecessor.
What's the word? The opposite of a
predecessor comes out. All right. Must
be a body double.
Uh Wars kind of looks like a reptilian.
His eyes are black. His eyes are too
black. We'll take a poll in the chat. Is
Kevin Walsh a reptilian shape shifter?
Let's take Let's start a poll. Is Kevin
Walsh?
Kevin
Wsh
is Kevin Walsh
a what the heck? What the heck? Hang on.
Is Kevin Worsh
a reptilian?
Let's see what you guys say.
Is Kevin Worsh a reptilian shape shifter
preparing for war? Says no, he's not.
He's not.
Let's see what's going to happen here
with this candle, man. I hope we dump
it. I hope we dump it.
All right. Big shout out to everybody in
the chat here. Um,
we shouldn't lust. Well, there are some
things it's okay to lust after, right?
Some things it's okay to lust after, you
know? At
least if you read the King James Bible,
go read Deuteronomy 16 in the King James
Bible.
Shout out to Around Town. He says, "I'm
out. I'm going to go wash my car."
Shout out to Flyman Hits and Chad PZ8Z.
Probably not just a tool. Look, yeah,
everyone the the you know, and I I the
reality is if you're going to be the the
chairman of the Federal Reserve,
you got to be a pretty pretty scummy
guy. I I hate to say that. You know,
when I say that, it's like, sheesh,
Jason, you don't even know these people.
But the reality is, if you're the
chairman of a privately owned company
that has knowingly been stealing
the wealth of generations,
[music]
uh, you got to be a pretty scummy
person. You got to be a pretty scummy
person. And then to get up there and
pretend like you have the the the
interest of the people in mind, you got
to be a really scummy person to do that.
You know, that could really turn a guy
from this into this. [laughter] You
know, obviously this is a really old
picture, guys, but let's pretend it's
not. This is the internet. The internet
is the place where you can take anything
and just run with it. It's been 2 weeks.
Kevin Walsh went from this to this and
two weeks from this to this cuz he
didn't he didn't wash his damn hands.
All right? You know, people don't know,
but washing your hands is pretty much
the same as Botox, right? You inject the
Botox. Look, I need some Botox myself.
Would you look at this?
Whoa, man. I'm so wrinkly. I'm so old.
Guys, don't do what I do. Do as I say,
not as I do. I'm out in the sun 12 hours
a day with no sunscreen, those UV
radiations.
Um, okay. Let's get back to the Bitcoin
chart here now. Again, so there's a few
things I'm looking for. Really, there's
a few places I'd be looking for. Place
number one obviously is along from
63.4ish.
We take our golden pocket from the low
to the high and this is the place where
if we dump I would look for a nice
bounce that would be a beautiful nice
support zone that we have here. Secondly
would simply to be to take the liquidity
from these lows here
and bounce from this daily order block
at around 62k.
And then of course the juiciest number
three place is to come down and back
test value area low because remember
we're looking at this as our sideways
range here. This is our sideways range.
And so if we can come down to the bottom
of the sideways range, right? That is
the place where we'd be looking for
another long trade to come back up to
the top of the sideways range. Now if we
just pump straight up from here,
obviously we'd be looking for shorts at
the top of this sideways range. We have
about 17 minutes until our good friend
WS starts telling us about everything
that he's planning to do with the
economy.
He feels good about it. In fact, I had a
conversation with him before the stream
and he he was telling me I said, "Kevin
Wash, are things looking good?" He said,
"Oh yeah, Jason." "Oh yeah." I said,
"Are you going to dump it?" He said, "Oh
no, no, no, no, no, no." Said, "You
going to pump it?" He's like, "Oh yeah,
baby." I said, "How can I trust you?"
His face changed a little bit. He got
real somber. You know, he never gave me
an answer. We got disconnected after
that. All right. We got disconnected
after that. Something strange happened.
The phone somehow got disconnected.
What's the story with you tattoos? What
do you mean what's the story with my
tattoos? What do you mean what's the
story? I walked into a tattoo shop. I
said, "Can you cover my entire arm with
ink?" They said, "Why?" I said, "Well,
cuz it's cool." They said, "What do you
want?" I said, "It doesn't matter. All
that matters is that people see I have
tattoos. That's all that matters. Cuz
then people will think I'm cool, man.
And I mean, look at this cool guy.
Tattoos. He must be like tough, you
know? He must be a real cool guy. You
can see they're really nothing. They're
just a complete conglomerate of
literally nothing. I mean, what the heck
is this even? I mean, it's it literally
doesn't It's just black ink, guys. You
know,
uh, Micro Strategy just started to pump.
Interesting.
Um,
man, I cannot wait for this press
conference cuz this green candle, this
15minute green candle. I wonder how much
time we have left on this 15-minute
green candle.
It's so funny to see the millennial
generation getting old. Us millennials
now, it was so cool to have tattoos
[laughter] when we were 19. Now it's
like, it's now, you know what it's like?
It's like when a guy who was into hair
metal in the 80s had a mullet in 2007.
had an 80s mullet in 2007. That's that's
what tattoos are like now. You know,
nobody had tattoos. Then my generation,
everyone got covered in tattoos. And now
we're old and they look stupid. You know
what? Now we got to live with our dang
decisions. Our parents were right. You
can't erase them. I've tried. I've
tried. I take the sandpaper and I rub
it. I rub it and I rub it. Nothing
happens. Nothing happens,
you know.
Let's see here.
What's going to Oh, whoa. We're getting
a little bit of a dump. Let's see how
this candle closes. Let's get Where's
our countdown? Can I get a countdown on
this? It's countdown to bar close. Boom.
All right. Okay. Fresh 15-minute candle
has just opened here. 15. This is the
candle. This fresh baby candle here. Do
you hear that? It's crying. A sweet baby
candle's crying. This baby candle is
crying just like the baby chick. Shout
out to the baby chick. and and shout out
to the the other egg that hatched into a
baby chick.
This new baby candle is going to lead
right up to the press conference and
right now it's looking a little bit
bullish. All right, it's looking a
little bit bullish. Let's go to the
12minut time frame here. My favorite
time frame. It's difficult to see what's
going to happen. We don't have bullish
divergence at the low. We don't have
bearish divergence at the high.
All right, we did have a bullish
divergence right over here. you know,
right over here. We did have that, but
those butt cheeks failed me big time,
guys. Sheesh, man. H man. I'm literally
an idiot, guys. You know, I feel like an
idiot right now. Can I freestyle about
crypto?
That's the only thing I know how to
freestyle about.
You know,
that's the only thing I know how to
freestyle about is crypto.
Tattoos are horrible for your immune
system. I've heard stuff like this. It
wouldn't surprise me. Honestly, it
wouldn't surprise me. Like, the more I
think about it. The older I get, the
more natural I get, the more I realize,
you know what? My entire ar like I don't
use soap. I don't use soap.
All right? I don't use deodorant, guys,
cuz I don't want any like gross who the
heck knows what on my skin to turn me
into a dang beta male. You know what I'm
saying?
And then I think to myself, I'm not
using I'm not using Old Spice body wash
cuz that stuff turns you into a shemail.
But I have tons of who the heck knows
what on my arm. I didn't read the dang
ingredients for this ink. I have no idea
what the heck is in my skin 24/7. I have
no idea. Maybe it is bad for your dang
immune system. I will tell you this,
sometimes the white ink in this arm,
which by the way, you can't even see the
white ink anymore cuz it's so dang faded
cuz I'm outside in the sun every day
with no sunscreen.
But the white ink sometimes randomly
gets inflamed and it itches, man. That
white ink itches, I'll tell you. Not the
black ink, the white ink. All right, the
white ink,
man. It's the white ink that's the real
problem. It's the white ink, right?
Soap is for suckers. Our pink doesn't
use water either.
Do I smell like a Jersey 7-Eleven?
I wish I did. Oh, man. Okay, so here we
go, guys. We're getting a move to the
downside. We have about 12 13 minutes
until the press conference. This
15-minute candle has 12 minutes left.
This is going to be the candle that uh
leads us right into the press
conference. All right, so let's see
what's going to happen here.
you know.
Let's see. Let's see.
Never in your life have butt cheeks
failed you. Well, the butt cheeks failed
me today. The butt cheeks failed me
today cuz this long trade, this juicy
long trade,
uh, right here, this juicy long trade,
this one here
for a negative $1,500,
right? This juicy long trade right here.
I'll tell you, we had the cheeks, baby.
We had the cheeks and they confirmed. We
had the confirmation of the dang cheeks.
six minute time frame. We had the cheeks
as well. Look at this. We had the cheeks
as well. One minute time frame. The one
minute was really got was what got me in
here. Look at this. We had the cheeks
and we came down to a nice support. We
came down to a local value area low. I
thought we could have a little pre FOMC
pump, baby. But we didn't. We didn't get
that. We did. We had a little pump. I
could have closed the trade in like
$1,000 of profit up here. When I saw
this pump here, I thought, "Yeah, this
that makes sense." I thought we were
going to come up and take all this.
[laughter]
I thought we were going to come up and
take this. I had a take profit set right
here.
Oh, the dang market makers, man. This
is, you know, this is where I question
everything. I question everything. I
question everything. You know,
man, I got to I got to get back in the
dang zone. I had to I had to get back
into that scalping mentality. Seriously,
you know what's been getting me wrecked
is not being in that scalping mentality.
Been trying to hold these dang trades
for too long. I have to have Crypto
Crank back on the dang show.
I use soap oil combined with fresh
omega-3 and some shrimp juice.
Do I think Garvey knows about the
cheeks?
I don't know.
Old Spice turns him into a shemail
and Jay is the most sensible in the
game. Oh my goodness. Yeah, I hope they
hunt these dang stop losses. Let's see.
You're You're at break even, Adam
Thomas. That's good, man. I'm You know,
last week and this week I'm
I'm down
I'm down like seven grand. I'm down like
seven grand, man. In the last week, I'm
down like seven grand.
Please check liquidity zone on Bitcoin.
Where to buy my merch? Uh at the website
jason caspertradingrading.com.
Let's see if we can go to that website.
jasonaspertrading.com.
>> Yeah. Yep. And go to this merch button
up here. Look, you can buy Casper Crew
hats. You could buy Dolores coffee mugs
with the unused butt cheeks. Who
wouldn't want to be sipping coffee from
one of these? You know what I'm saying?
You could buy a a Casper Crew tank top,
chicken with uneven butt cheeks.
You could buy a chicken's drinking water
t-shirt. You could buy Dolores a Dolores
t-shirt. I remember I wore this shirt
once to a family uh was I think it was a
family reunion on my wife's side and
people were like, "What the heck is
that?" I said, "Oh, you know, Dolores."
They're like Dolores. Yeah. You know,
the waitress at the diner, the one with
the raspy voice like this who talks like
this. You know, she's got uneven butt
cheeks, so she always spills the coffee
right on top of his.
They're like, "No, I never heard of
her." I'm like, "You never heard of
Dolores? You know, the one who smokes
inside like it's still the ' 80s.
Surprisingly, no one in my wife's family
ever heard of Dolores."
That's a good thing. Everyone in my
wife's family thinks I'm just a total
bum.
You know, they know I'm unemployed.
That's the thing. They all know I'm
unemployed. They feel so bad for my
wife. She has to support me and my
habits of leverage trading longing the
top. All right, here we go, guys. 8
minutes until the press conference.
8 minutes and we are getting a bit of a
dumperonian cheese. Let's see if we
can't come down. Man, that would be
amazing.
That would be amazing if we could just
come down a little bit.
Just a wee bit yonder.
Come on, Bitcoin.
Your wife's name is Dolores.
Hector Rodriguez. His wife's name is
Dolores.
Bro, do you need help? Because you talk
so fast. It's like you don't breathe
air. It's crazy. I talk fast. I'm always
hyped, guys. I'm always hyped up, right?
I'm always hyped up on life. All right.
They don't even ask smoking or
non-smoking at that diner.
All right. Well, shout out to Vincent
US
Christ 15. You're new. He's new and he
thinks I'm funny and weird. Well, thanks
for thanks for checking out the stream.
Um,
shout out to Led Start. You haven't been
here in 2 years. Well, welcome to the
show, man. Welcome back after two years.
We got seven minutes. It's been two
years.
Two years.
Two years. We got 7 minutes and it's
been 2 years.
Hey yo, 7 minutes, 2 years. Jay Casper
out here like Britany Spears. Now sit
back, [music] relax, baby. Open up your
ears cuz I'm about to tell you how you
can be cheered. Cheer up. [music] Don't
be sad. It's not bad. Bitcoin dumping
down just like we had to long [music]
the top high leverage. Now we sit down
and we about to drink a beverage. The
lower uneven [music]
butt cheeks, baby. I like what I see.
Maybe we got the bullish dib as the
price is coming down. Your butt's coming
up. J C is a [music] clown. And we get
in the Bugatti around the town driving
around. Can you hear the sound? The
Bitcoin price [music] about to dump into
the ground. And once we hunt liquidity,
then we turn around. Ah, here we go.
Make sure to [music] wash your hands as
you get into the car. It stands the same
as it did last month. No change
inflation. [music]
And then we get the pump. Kevin War. How
do you do? So happy, so sad, so happy,
so glad. And then he turns mad. From
this to this, he didn't get the Botox.
[music] Bitcoin, baby. Straight into the
butttox. Uh, we got the uneven candle.
About to turn [music] red. Baby, let me
sniff your sandals. Uh, and I can't even
get a handle. But I'm high from sniffing
the candles. We got [music] a wick to
the top to be tick. Market makers back
to the tricks. Licking their lips. You
know they want to do [music] it like the
flakes you got on your cheeks. Here we
go. Bitcoin. Listen to me. [music] 5
minutes left until the conference.
Bitcoin like a trance. What's a trance
you ask? I don't know. But sit back and
welcome to [music] the Jason Casper
show. We got the 50minute candle coming
out. I can't get a handle.
But I'm still wearing sandals on the
treadmill. We're counting down the
candles. Fake Castler, [music]
we're in the house. We're looking for
the [singing] dump for the next bounce.
And oh snap, baby. Let me take a peek to
see if Marcus Cipher B has any uneven
butt [music] cheeks. We want big on the
left side, nice and juicy, skinny on the
right to round out the booty. And I
don't even know if you can spot it,
[music] but we're coming down to the
golden pocket.
All right, we got five minutes still
left, baby.
5 minutes still left, baby.
My goodness.
H, we found Jason sniffing sandals.
Jason the sandal sniffer.
My goodness.
You've been here since 2023. That's
what's up. That's right. I I'm only
giving it straight, you know.
Um,
my goodness. My goodness.
All right, we got four minutes until the
press conference, guys, and we are
getting a little bit of a dump down
here. Now, what I don't want is I don't
want a back test of the of the golden
pocket. No, no, sorry, Bob. No, sorry,
Bob. We're at the golden pocket right
now. We need to lose this support. We
need to lose this support. No change. We
stay the same for days.
you know, the the purple box of hope and
wonder to bring us down to the liquidity
grab here. We'll pull we'll pull the
macro fib is what I want to see. All
right,
let's let's load up our press
conference. Actually, crap. We We are
bouncing from the golden pocket, by the
way. That's not what I want to see,
guys. I don't want to bounce from the
purple box, but let's let's go ahead and
get our dang our dang thing started
here.
All right, let's see here. Let's see.
Where is the Federal What the heck?
Where is the Federal Reserve here?
Here we go. Yeah, this is what we need.
All right, we're going to load this up
while we wait.
While we wait
while we wait, we'll load it up. We'll
load up the press conference. Kevin
Walsh.
Going to see what happens here with good
old Kevin Walsh.
Um, yeah, good old Kevin Walsh, man.
While we wait,
you know what? We'll while we wait. Uh,
yeah. You know what? Yeah. You know
what? Yeah. Let Let me Let me Let me go
pee now. I'm going to go pee while we
wait for Kevin Worsh. We still got two
minutes. There's nothing worse than a
conference with a full bladder. It's
raining out here pretty hard, guys. All
right, it is raining out here pretty
hard. So,
yeah. Let's see. My favorite tree to pee
in.
Yeah, this is the one. All right, let's
see. Locked and loaded.
Uh, load up the bowl.
Hope you guys aren't smoking drugs out
there.
Ah, we're bouncing from the pocket.
We call it one the copper pocket. Okay,
the copper pocket.
Jmatt's been here since I had my wallet
drained. Wow, you're a real OG, man.
Shout out to Ant Sutton85. 12minute
build looking invalidated. Yeah, I think
it does look invalidated. I I did try to
take a long and it didn't [music] work.
I'll bet people were expecting a much
bigger pump. I don't know. I honestly I
don't think people expect anything
anymore from this nonsense. [music]
Yeah, it's been raining for days. Yeah,
it really has. It was really sunny this
morning.
Um, [music]
yeah, it was really sunny this morning,
but now it's cloudy out. Look at this.
You guys see that? You guys see that?
It's cloudy. It's cloudy as all. Get
out. Cloudy as all. Get out. Telling
you. All right, back to the treadmill,
baby. Life is like a treadmill to me.
Life is like a treadmill. I just can't
stop getting my steps in. Where's the
Where is the
Yeah, I can't stop getting those steps
in, guys. Addicted to the steps,
you know. Addicted to the steps. [music]
>> All right, one minute until the press
conference starts.
Let's go ahead and get that rolling.
Let's get that rolling here. Let's close
off this music and let's put back on our
our Kevin W anthem here. Our Kevin Wash
anthem
Good Today,
my second FOMC committee meeting as
chairman has come quickly. It's probably
too early to call it a streak, but our
discussions again were colleial and
constructive.
I'm truly lucky to work with colleagues
so capable and mission focused and so
determined like I am to sharpen the
performance of the Federal Reserve.
Today, as you know, our committee
decided to vote by a nineto-3 vote to
maintain the target range for the
federal funds rate at three and one half
to three and threequarters percent. The
committee is continuing its policy of
making ample reserves in the banking
system.
The economy is showing impressive
resilience
even with recent shocks. The trends are
positive and reveal solid growth. Job
gains have kept pace with the workforce
and the unemployment rate has changed
little.
Inflation remains elevated relative to
the committee's 2% goal. The committee
remains resolute. You've heard this
before, but we will deliver price
stability.
As before, the policy statement conveys
just the facts. It's steering clear of
forecasting, a choice we consider
especially prudent at these uncertain
times.
Uncertainty, however, does not mean a
lack of clarity. For some households,
businesses, and market professionals,
five years of high inflation have left a
mistaken impression that's hard to
shake, that the Fed's implicit inflation
target was somehow above 2%. Let me
reiterate, there is no soft inflation
target. There is no soft implicit
target. Not on this committee's watch.
There's only a target and it's 2%.
Not one of my FOMC colleagues is under
any illusion.
We have begun a new chapter and we
understand that the five plus years of
inflation above target cannot be cured
in nine weeks or by a single month of
modest price decreases.
This Fed will not waver. Our credibility
rests on performing our duties and
delivering on our responsibilities.
Americans are right to expect that
because our nation's prosperity depends
on it. To the regulars here in the press
room, today's assessment might sound
familiar. Yet, there was nothing
inertial about our discussions, our
policy, or our strategy.
Two economic developments are worth
highlighting. The first is a very
notable change since our last meeting 42
days ago. Nominal and real yields are
materially higher across the Treasury
curve. In fact, some of the increases in
market interest rates between FOMC
meetings are among the most significant
in the last two decades, ranking around
the top decile or so.
But if the committee didn't change its
policy rate, what happened? In the
intermedating period, market attention
centered on real data and real economic
developments.
Prices reacted in real time to incoming
information,
and the reduction in forward guidance
may have been a factor.
Market participants are learning to play
the ball, not the referee.
And market prices will continue to
respond in the direction and magnitude
they see fit.
This is in my view a change for the
better and we're just getting started.
After all, the central bank need not
always and everywhere be the center of
attention.
I understand the desire for rolling
forecasts and commentary from this
committee,
but for our part, we need to observe
market reaction to developments direct
and unfiltered.
I want to stress, of course, that
decisions by this committee matter a
great deal
and where necessary and appropriate, we
will not hesitate to act.
A second economic development is one
that I noted at the congressional
oversight hearings this month, but it's
worth repeating.
The most striking feature of the economy
is the strong growth of business
investment.
The surge in high-tech capex has been
remarkable,
but that does not necessarily make the
Fed's role any easier. In the AI related
category of high techch equipment and
software, the most recent data shows
four quarter growth rates of nearly 20%.
This is helping to sustain the healthy
momentum of manufacturing output. More
generally, CAPEX is preparing the ground
for future growth.
Nonetheless, the precise timing and
magnitude of effects on the supply side
remain hard to predict.
FOMC meetings produce policy decisions,
but just as important is candid
discussion of the big things that matter
most.
That too is a priority in this new
chapter at the Fed.
In our meeting, vigorous discussion
centered on four questions which I will
enumerate.
First, we talked a lot about the
implications of the past five years of
high inflation on the current policy
conjuncture
to an to echo an old phrase, has the
past really passed?
Second,
my colleagues and I considered the
economic shocks of recent years,
strained supply chains arising from the
pandemic, military conflicts, energy
supply disruptions,
substantial increases in tariff rates,
and yes, the surge in AI related
investment.
These differ in their sources. Do they
also differ in their effects on output
and employment?
Third, we took up the related question
of price increases arising from shocks.
The business capex boom, for example, is
driving up prices of memory and logic
chips and associated AI infrastructure.
Do these changes indicate a broader
inflationary dynamic or do we just focus
on them because they are under the
bright street light?
Finally, we discuss monetary policy
tools and strategies for achieving
stable prices.
If, as the Fed has long held, interest
rate policy should be its primary
monetary policy instrument, how much
accommodation are we getting from the
balance sheet? In all of this, our work
is advancing at the Fed.
We're asking the right questions and in
this consequential time we know how very
much depends on getting the right
answers. Of course, you've all arrived
with questions of your own. So, let's
turn to them now.
>> Let's start with Steve.
>> Uh, thank you for taking our questions,
Mr. Chairman. Um you've had a couple
months now or nine weeks or whatever
number it is um to see the markets
behave in the absence of uh forward
guidance. I'm wondering if you could
tell me what message are you getting
from the markets as to where policy
ought to be right now.
>> Yeah. So I think officially it's eight
weeks and four days, but uh I'm not
counting. Uh the message from markets is
the message from markets. What I've
really been trying to do, Steve, as I
think you appreciate, your colleagues
appreciate is getting an unfiltered
message from markets, getting a direct
message. um letting buyers and sellers
meet at prices for treasuries, for the
foreign exchange value of the dollar,
and then trying to judge for ourselves
what does that mean about our remitt?
How are we doing on inflation? How are
we doing on employment? Um we're trying
not to interfere with that market
signal. That's part of the reason why
we've been somewhat spare in our words,
why we pulled back from forward
guidance. So, they're reacting to
events, I would say, much more directly
over the 42 days since we last met. This
is a good thing. As I mentioned in the
prepared remarks, we've seen a material
tightening not just in nominal rates,
but in real rates, too. And um we're
observing it. We're trying to stay out
of that because, you know, many of you
might be interested in our reaction
function. We're interested in the
reaction of financial markets.
>> I I I get that, Mr. chairman and I guess
the follow-up question is if the markets
are talking to you what do you hear them
saying and if it's real rates are higher
it would suggest that that's where the
funds rate ought to go
>> yeah so in
>> sorry
>> I'm sorry it's your question
>> so uh um interpreting markets is an
imperfect business we central bankers
like market pros can think these things
are overdetermined But let me offer uh
some speculation.
First, as we said in the FOMC statement
that you got at two o'clock, the economy
output is solid. Uh capex and
productivity are strong. Uh labor
markets solid, steady. Um the bond
market, the treasury market, it seems to
be saying that as well. If I were to try
to break down, disagregate the Treasury
market signals, I wouldn't be able to do
it perfectly. But the bond market's
saying many of those same things, and
that's why we're seeing a tightening
both in nominals and in reals. Even
while at some level we haven't done much
in 42 days, uh the markets have done
quite a bit.
>> Claire,
thank you.
>> Claire Jones, Financial Times. Um you
seem to have got the family fight you
were after at this meeting. We saw um we
saw three we saw three descents. Um
could you characterize the arguments
that those dissenters put forward please
and tell us a little bit why you weren't
persuaded by them at this stage. Thank
you.
>> So I guess I shouldn't give you their
best arguments. I'll give you some
others. Um so you're right. I asked for
a good family fight and I got one.
That's the purpose. That's the design
feature. I come into th this meeting,
even this press conference, heartened by
what I've experienced the last two days.
Most of our discussion were on the big
questions that matter to the conduct of
monetary policy. We we didn't sort of
hide from them. We weren't scared of
them. There was a lot more interaction
between and among my colleagues. It was
a real family fight. Um my view, which
you've long heard, is uh that's the
better way to get policy right. That's
our north star. So there was a lot of
agreement that I heard that we have the
powers, the tools, also the authority to
deliver stable prices. No walking back
from our responsibilities.
Um there was a large majority support
for the decision that we made in the
room. But I also want to leave you cla
with one other impression. There was
nothing inertial about that discussion.
It was an active robust discussion about
what's in the full range of what we can
do and might want to do in the period
ahead. Um you characterized accurately
there was a disagreement about a
decision today. I would say that doesn't
sort of capture the full essence of the
discussion. Um the path to central bank
heaven requires delivering on our remit.
These days that means delivering on
price stability. I wouldn't measure that
path in 42 days or any one particular
meeting and I came out of that meeting
even more confident that this is the
right team to win the battle against
high inflation.
>> How much do you think um not going in
July was down to the cool CPI print for
June?
So in two words, not much. Not much. Um
I'd like to believe that the committee
shares my views which is the historic
problem with data dependence is the data
and the dependence. We are not relying
on any one individual piece of data as
cover or as an excuse or as validation.
Um what I care about and what I think
the committee cares about is trends on
the data. Um sure we got some
encouraging inflation data. I think at
the meeting 42 days ago I said something
like 63 months of inflation above
target. I didn't say 64 though the final
calculation might might be a close one.
So we'll be we'll be watching inflation
data over the period ahead. But I also
don't want you to leave the
misimpression that we're sort of
breathlessly waiting that um I've called
for a task force to revisit both the
private and public data we use to make
our decision-m that task force is
outdoing their work. I'll be checking
back in with them the next couple of
weeks, but I wouldn't say we overly
relied on on any one piece of data,
including that data which surprised some
a couple of weeks ago.
Neil.
>> Hi, Chairman Worsh. Thanks, Neil Irwin
with Axios. Thank you for taking our
questions. Um, so the Fed funds rate is
now about 75 basis points below the
two-year yield. Uh, suggest markets
think you'll have to tighten eventually.
About 100 basis points below most tailor
rule estimates. You're hitting your
employment mandate. Inflation stays
high. Why should rates not be higher
today?
>> There's a lot in there, Neil. Um,
so rates are higher today than they were
42 days ago.
Um, markets have made decisions because
we step back in part from trying to
influence those. Market judgments have
moved up on what nominal rates are
across the Treasury curve. That doesn't
mean we take them as by dictation, but
we're observing them. So, I think it's a
mischaracterization to say that markets
haven't reacted because we didn't move
today. Markets are reacting in real
time. Uh in the period ahead, we've got
important decisions to make about the
policy rate. Markets in the intervening
period, I think, have quite a bit of uh
decisions to make. I'll see if I can put
it this way. Uh monetary policy matters
not just by what we say or even what we
do. Monetary policy matters by how it
affects the real economy. and these
prices that we see in financial markets
is one of the many ways in which it
affects the real economy. Um we'll be
continuing to watch that market
information, see how it responds to
incoming events and that can help inform
our decision-m when we meet in seven or
eight weeks.
>> How would you characterize of the in the
family fight the last couple of days of
you and the other eight members who
wanted to hold? Was that a strong
conviction or was that a hair trigger uh
uh close call on holding versus
tightening?
Well, I think uh you know the vote the
vote was 9 to3. Um
the broader discussion to my ear over
the course of the last days showed a lot
of agreement on the hard questions. Uh
the four questions I raised at the
outset about what's really happening in
the economy with the shocks and absent
the shocks. What are our tools and our
capabilities?
um uh what's the effect on prices on
output? I heard a lot of commonality on
the questions. Were there different
leans on the answers? You bet there was.
Um so could people come to different
conclusions? Absolutely. But my own
judgment is um this is a period of
watchful thinking, not watchful waiting.
And I think the score on that vote was
unanimous.
Uh, Colby,
>> thank you. Colobby Smith with the New
York Times. You've mentioned that
looking at the Fed's policy tools is one
element of a three-prong strategy to
address the inflation problem. So, I'm
curious how you view the effectiveness
of those tools. If inflation is too high
and not coming down, is the best remedy
to raise interest rates?
>> So, that's that was the discussion in
the last two days. Is that the dominant
remedy? If inflation continues to be
elevated through the forecast period,
interest rates could well be part of
that solution, but I wouldn't say it's
in isolation. Um, I tried to describe in
my remarks today a point that I made in
to the oversight committees a couple of
weeks ago. I think there was a
misimpression by some in financial
markets, by some households and
businesses that central bankers like me,
we set a 2% inflation target, but maybe
we were more tolerable of a somewhat
higher inflation target. In economics,
we'd call that the revealed preference.
And so, might it have been rational for
people to think, well, their inflation
target somewhat higher. The what I heard
in the last two days, what I've heard in
eight and a half weeks is no, we will
deliver the 2% inflation target. That is
the committee's definition of price
stability. So, one way absent the tools
that you reference to ensure that we get
there is ensure that expectations are
centered around the right number. Um,
and I think we've made some progress on
that. I am not suggesting we're done on
that. It's worth reiterating. And
ultimately the business we're in Colby
is performance. We are going to be
judged by how we perform. Um and that's
what we intend to do. The inflation
target making clear expectations is one
part of it. Making sure we demonstrate
we're responsible for it. We're not
blaming as another. And our policy tools
like you referenced is the third and uh
equally consequential part. How are you
factoring the fact that a large portion
of the inflation overshoot is being
caused by supply shocks as it's
mentioned again in in the statement?
Does that blunt the effectiveness of
rate hikes in your view?
>> Um, first on the premise of your
question, it was almost as if you were
listening to our discussion in the last
day and a half. A lot of our focus was
on trying to understand and identify
underlying inflation dynamics amid
shocks.
We take these shocks seriously. There
have been a series of them that have
been hitting this economy. We're not
looking through them and saying, "Oh,
they don't matter." But we're trying to
understand is to what extent are these
shocks broadening in their effects,
broadening in their impact on prices
that are quite far removed from it. Our
goal is to have growth that is
broadening and inflation that is
becoming more limited, more
circumscribed. Uh, I'll be the first to
admit the shocks make this job and this
policy conjuncture a little tougher, but
that's among the chief questions we've
asked ourselves and around the room
people have different views on it. I
tend to think in the coming months we're
going to refine that view and have a
better judgment and we're going to have
market prices trying to help inform it
too.
>> Edward.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. uh Edward
Lawrence from Fox Business. I guess I
want to drill down maybe a little bit.
What specifically in your mind would be
the argument then for a pause today?
>> So I wouldn't characterize what we did
as anything like a pause. I would
characterize what we did as a rigorous
review of the economic situation.
I would characterize what we did as a
review of the big hard questions and I'd
characterize it as a view of what our
own homework is to try to resolve those
questions in the period ahead. Um, if
you were to try to force a description
that this was a pause, I would say
financial market prices would take the
other side of that. Financial market
prices in this intermedating period,
they didn't pause. They reacted to the
inflation data in one direction, strong
economic growth in the other direction.
Um, and uh, nominal and real rates went
up. Did the Fed take an explicit change
in its policy rate today? No. But I
think that's the beginning of the story,
not the end of the story.
>> And if I could, I did want to ask, not
forward guidance, but looking forward.
Traditionally, a Federal Reserve
chairman uses the Jackson Hole summit as
as a sort of a reset of monetary policy.
How do you look at the speech that
you're going to make in August?
>> I look at it like a blank piece of paper
right now. Um I I have not begun
consideration with the incredible team
here what would go into that document.
Um I think you characterized it
correctly. Historically, at least from
my first tour of duty at the Fed to more
recent periods, it would be sort of a
setting up speech more often than not of
what was going to be happening in the
fall. I haven't made any judgments on
that, but um those are judgments we'll
have to come to. If I could, in the high
mountain air in Jackson, Wyoming, I'd
like to also frame the big questions.
There is a tendency, especially with the
proliferation of meetings and press
conferences, to get caught up in the
myopic. Did you do this by a quarter or
do that?
Ultimately whether we deliver on price
stability matters some the decisions we
make in six or seven or eight week
periods but they matter more what are
the big questions what's really
happening with productivity what's
really happening with demographics
what's really happening to the global
economy amid the shocks um haven't made
a decision whether it's going to be a
big picture speech or whether it's going
to be a more traditional setup for all
the action we're going to have between
September and December. I will tell you
one other thing that I am doing between
now and Jackson Hole, which is I'm
checking in with those task forces. Um,
my first principle of establishing a
task force is find the best subject
matter experts anywhere in the world and
put them together, especially put them
together with other people who might
disagree with them. Uh, in the next
couple weeks, I'm going to be doing a
check back in. Uh, I've given them time
to sort of think hard about their
agenda, their debate, their schedule,
and when they might be ready for prime
time. I'll be do a little bit of that
checking and uh that may or may not
inform anything I have to say in
Jackson.
>> Nick
Tamaros of the Wall Street Journal. Uh,
Chairman Wars, I want to follow up on
Col's question um about policy
transmission. You've said there's no
cruel choice between stable prices and
full employment. Um rates bring
inflation down by cooling demand. It's
generally thought that can show up in
the labor market. If that's not the
channel you're relying on, what is?
>> Yeah. So, let me go back to first
principles, Nick. Um
I don't believe that uh either part of
our mandate is generally at war with the
other part. I do not believe that price
stability and full employment is an
eitheror proposition. Um there have been
policy makers uh over the last several
generations who have thought that there
is a strict trade-off there. That isn't
my judgment. In fact, my judgment is if
and when we deliver on our remitt, we're
going to be satisfying both prongs.
We're going to have price stability and
full employment. And in fact, if you
want to do the most harm to the labor
markets, you would run a period of high
inflation that's variable such that
employers, businesses wouldn't really
know what's going on. So, I think the
two parts of our mandate are equally
important. We have no legislative
orphans here. I've been talking mostly
about price stability because we're
doing pretty well collectively as a
country as policy makers on the full
employment side but we're doing
considerably less well on prices that's
why we describe them as elevated and
that's what's taken most of our
discussion um in terms of transmission
mechanisms of monetary policy I think
different tools work through different
transmission mechanisms the interest
rates work through lending channels and
credit channels maybe confidence
channels and foreign exchange. The
balance sheet probably works through
some other channels like signaling and
portfolio balance. We're keeping full a
breast of all these tools in making
policy. But if the suggestion is somehow
we're going to be fine-tuning aggregate
demand so it catches supply, that's not
my mental model. I don't think we're
great in the fine-tuning business. We're
trying to get supply and demand in broad
order, but really what we're doing as we
sit here today at this press conference
is I think we've got a reasonable sense
of what aggregate demand looks like in
this economy. We're inferring aggregate
supply. We're making a judgment about
what productivity is. And in some sense,
there's a race between supply and
demand. and the surge in business capex
in around AI, it's making that
calculation a little harder to judge,
but in the period ahead, we're going to
be trying to judge just that.
>> And if I could ask, where exactly was
the disagreement today? Was it about the
inflation forecast or was it something
more around the the the risks uh the
tactics?
>> Yeah. So, I'm going to let the I'll let
the denters speak for themselves. Um,
the way I heard it over the last two
days was overwhelming agreement on
objectives and authority and commitment.
I didn't hear anybody walking away from
it. Um, the judgments as to how best to
achieve the price stability. That was
probably the question that we were
trying to answer. Um, what's the best
move? What's the best strategy? Um,
what's the best way to achieve it? And a
second question that was asked is when
do we need to make those harder calls?
When do we need to make those decisions?
And like I said to one of your
colleagues, uh I was comforted that
markets in the intermedating period
weren't reacting to us. They weren't
reacting to dots or to speeches. They
appeared more than ever to be reacting
to real-time events. So they're gauging
themselves the how restrictive
uh the Treasury curve should be and that
I think has been a a useful development.
We don't endorse any particular market
move but I'd also suggest we observe
them with keen interest.
>> Jell
Janelle Marte with Bloomberg. Uh
following up on that, there was more
uncertainty in the markets about what
the Fed would do at this meeting. To
some extent, you might think that's what
you want to see, but my question is
about is there a point at which you
would not want to surprise the markets
if they were pricing in something with
higher certainty that was opposite of
what you were intended to do? What are
the risks that you see associated with
that?
>> Yes. So, it's a good question. Surprise
is not the objective function.
surprise is not um what we're solving
for. We have a clear north star. What
we're solving for is how to make the
best decisions.
Almost everything else should be in
service to that goal.
By not spoon feeding markets, by not
previewing our decisions, by not sort of
giving nudges and leans, my colleagues
and I have found in the intermedating
period, what we're getting is the views
from a very accomplished economist.
That's the internals of financial
markets. Instead of just uh repeating or
echoing what we are saying back to us,
they're giving us somewhat not perfect,
their own judgment. Um so uh surprises
are not the objective but at the same
time I would say we didn't come into
this meeting feeling constrained at by
the full range of alternatives we had in
front of us.
>> So some of your peers have continued to
discuss how they think about policy
decisions and if you don't offer your
reaction function or your way of
thinking about it how concerned are you
that you're seating control of the
narrative? So, not very concerned. Uh,
that's a short answer to the question.
Um, when some people that follow the Fed
say, "Well, we don't want your forecast.
We don't want your dot. We just want
your reaction function." Part of me
hears the what we really want is your
forecast. What we really want is your
dot. In terms of reaction function, let
me sort of disabuse
uh people of a question that may or may
not be real and be out there.
any central banker
uh especially a central banker where uh
the labor markets are more or less at
equilibrium.
Any central banker when he or she sees
underlying inflation moving higher he or
she is more inclined to tighten policy
again. when you've achieved the other
side of your mandate and you see
underlying inflation falling,
he's more inclined to loosen policy.
That's my reaction function and uh I
don't suspect it will uh cause people to
not continue to pry for more because the
truth is for a very long time in a lot
of countries coming out of the 2008
crisis. We're in crisis mode we were
purposefully providing a lot of
information trying to provide a lot of
assurance trying to tell people exactly
what we're going to do offering forward
guidance with clarity as if we're tying
our own hands behind our back. Well, in
crisis mode, that strikes me as a very
prudent policy. But in more benign
conditions, it strikes me as worth
revisiting. But markets and market
participants and reporters have learned
to devour all that information. So, I
take seriously that the pullback of
forward guidance requires some
transition. Reform isn't easy, but our
general judgment is going to help us
make better decisions and in so doing
satisfy our remit.
Paul
>> thank you. Um when you talk about the 2%
inflation target, what measure are you
relying on?
>> Yeah. So I'll give two answers. First,
let me give the proper standard answer.
the um the Federal Reserve every January
outlines a statement of purposes and
strategy. And in that strategy document,
which I believe was dated January of
this year, it describes a measure of PC
inflation as the as the objective
function there. Um I have enough of my
So that's our number. We're sticking
with it. Who knows come after next
January what we might say about
strategy. I suspect the task forces
might might have something to add. But
I'll say this, some version of the Lucas
critique, some version of Goodart's law
and economics should remind us that when
we talk about uh measures of inflation
or something else and we describe those
measures as being consistent with our
objectives,
we might make them such that they're not
very good measures or very good
objectives.
broadly if you said to me standing in
front of you I abide fully by the
strategy document we're going to deliver
2% inflation and not a whisper more
but to achieve that I'm looking at a
broader set of inflation data than PCE
so without sort of fully revealing my
cards um I'm trying to understand like
my colleagues what's the underlying
generalized change in prices that are
happening in the economy it is not a
perfect science. Um I might have said 42
days ago I've got a task force for that.
But we have a data project that's trying
to look and see whether we can't
separate the noise from the signal. And
so if you would hear a message from me,
yes, I care about what the PCE prints
are. I care about what the contributions
are from CPI and everything else, but my
my lens is broader than that. Uh even
though the remitt is quite narrow.
McKe,
>> Michael McKe from Bloomberg Radio and
Television. Uh,
I'm struggling a little bit with some of
what you've said today and maybe you can
help clarify this. Uh, you've said over
and over again that your job is to bring
down prices to get prices stable to hit
your target and that you will hit your
target. the market says you're not there
yet because they've raised rates. Uh but
all you've talked about today is talking
about it and it's not like members of
the committee weren't there before you
talking about it. So I guess what the
American people might be asking is what
are you waiting for? Yeah. So believe it
or not, this press conference is not all
I've done today. Um, we have spent an
inordinate amount of time in the last
two, two days, two weeks
looking at our monetary policy strategy,
evaluating our tools, um, thinking hard
about the sources of data that we have
at our disposal and we wish we had.
We've also thought hard about the period
ahead. What among these questions will
be answered with more clarity, certainly
not certainty. So the decision we'd made
today, the discussion we had in that
room was the farthest thing from inertia
I can imagine as a point estimate at
this very moment in a choice between two
alternatives. You heard the results of
it. But I would tell you that this
discussion was far more robust and our
thinking about how best to achieve that
target is advanced and over the coming
months I expect it to be advanced much
more significantly. If you were to sort
of if I were to steal a follow-up
question, I won't let you you won't be
giving it up. If I were to steal a
follow-up question, well, what's what's
what's the world think about what you've
done? I would again reiterate what we do
isn't just about what we say. It's not
just about what we do in the performance
business.
Um and so so if I look at the Treasury
curve, if I look at the dollar, if I
look at a lot of things that are
internals inside of financial markets, I
think what they're broadly saying is um
that this committee does own it, has the
credibility to deliver it, and they
believe like I do that we will. Um uh
but I don't want to leave you with a
misimpression. We've got no magic wand.
uh this isn't something that we're going
to be able to carry out in days or
weeks, but we're going to deliver on the
responsibility that Congress gave us and
today's meeting and the preparation for
today's meeting was an important step
towards that destination.
Uh, I'd like to follow up on the task
forces as well and ask what vetting did
you do of the people that you appointed
to the task forces in particular given
Mark Andre's substantial political
spending $25 million in just the past
year to back candidates who oppose
stricter I AI regulation. How can the
public be confident that a committee he
co-chairs will provide an independent
assessment of AI's economic effects
rather than one aligned with the
interests of the AI industry?
>> Yeah. So, I selected 15
uh incredible subject market subject
matter experts to tackle five of the
most important questions that if we get
the answers right, we're going to do a
far better job in delivering. And if we
get the answers wrong, we have a
problem. The comfort that I can give you
and your listeners is we're the decision
makers. Uh the chairman of the board of
the Federal Reserve and the members of
the board and the FOMC, we will be the
consumers of the outputs from five
different committees. The judgments
we're making will be informed by but not
at all determined by these outside
groups. Um my theory of the case in
establishing the task forces were to
pick people with extraordinary talent
uh depth of expertise and a divergence
of views inside every committee so they
too can have a family fight. Um this is
not outsourcing to people that aren't
known and haven't been vetted. This is
seeing whether new ideas can catalyze a
broader, better, more informed
discussion inside the room. And I'm very
confident that we're gonna be able to do
that. I am impressed by the credentials
of these 15 people. And full disclosure,
I've known almost all of them for a very
long time. And I think they're going to
give their best views on the subject.
But ultimately, these are decisions
we're going to make and we're
accountable to our oversight committees
and to the remitt Congress gave us to
deliver.
>> Hi, Ann Saphir with Reuters. Nice to see
you again. Um, so I need a little help
here, too. You've you've said repeatedly
you have no tolerance for inflation. Um
and yet we are seeing above target
inflation repeatedly for five years and
through your term so far and sure you
have no magic wand but you have not
taken action. You just gave us a little
peek at your reaction function as well.
You said that if underlying inflation is
rising that you would tend to uh think
that you might need to tighten and with
the exception of the most recent
inflation print that is what we've been
seeing. So could you explain what you
mean by no tolerance for inflation and
what you plan to do about it?
>> Sure. So Ann, I hear from you what I
hear more broadly from households and
businesses. Impatience.
Deliver it already. Um this is not a
this is not an excuse. This is a fact.
This FOMC this board has been in
business for eight and a half weeks. Um
the the the
patience the impatience that households
and businesses feel have been going on
for 63 months. Um, we are on the job. We
will deliver. We are focused like a
laser on making sure we can do it. Um,
but the suggestion that we're going to
be able to do it with our magic wand is
one I want to disabuse you and everyone
else of. But the discussion the last two
days give me more confidence even than I
had eight and a half weeks ago. this
team that we have at the FOMC, the
support that we have from board staff
and the new hard questions we're asking,
we need to resolve those. And as we
resolve those questions, get smarter on
those, we're going to deliver on the
remitt. Um, you don't have to take my
word for it. Uh if you look broadly at
uh market prices, they are certainly not
saying all clear, but they are working
in concert to to keep us on our toes and
they have tightened financial conditions
in this intrammeting period. and um and
that has given us uh uh that has
provided us some some some comfort that
uh that we've got the ability and
capability to deliver
>> and and and is your um read or your I
guess faith in March September meeting
and markets are seeing a near 100%
chance of a rate hike as they see now.
How does that
feed into your
>> But if we're trying to land the plane
and deliver 2% inflation
and we take a very useful source of
information and we get it all fogged up
[snorts] by giving it our own forecasts,
by providing rolling commentary, I can
assure you that we're going to have less
information, less ability to land the
plane successfully and deliver price
stability. We're just trying to make
sure that that source of information is
as direct and unfiltered as possible. It
isn't to the exclusion of data sources
and opinions and other surveys, but if
you're hearing from me, we wanted to
make sure we were getting a better
source of information. I think in a
relatively short time we are.
>> We'll go to Brian Chung for the last
question.
>> Hi there, Chairman Worsh. Brian Chung
with NBC News. Um, so you said you'd be
open to having press conferences when
there's news to make. So today, no
change to rates, no forward guidance for
the average household, I guess. What was
the news today? Um, so apparently it was
news that I had a press conference. Um,
let me just see if I can offer some
clarity on that. Between now and year
chairman feels better about this board
and this committee's ability to deliver
than I did when I showed up here on the
first day. And I showed up pretty
confident. Um I've been heartened by the
reception that I received. Uh no doubt
in some of your uh commentaries today,
you'll talk about a divided Federal
Reserve. Boy, that's not the feeling I
felt the last couple of days and the
couple days before it. what I felt was a
group of professionals all with
different perspectives, different views,
different judgments, but eager to roll
up their sleeves and have a family fight
and eager to reform the way in which the
Fed does policy. A keenness and
open-mindedness and curiosity about that
so we have a far better chance to
deliver on the remitt that Congress gave
us. And so I want to leave you with the
optimism of a new central banker that
we're committed as ever to deliver and
to offer an assurance we will. Thank you
all very much.
Well,
that was that was that man. And I have
to say
I do miss Jerome Pow.
I do miss Jerome Powell
after all that. Sheesh, man. What a
weird weird
press conference. So,
you know,
hang on. Let me close this thing out
here.
All right. Well, here's the thing, guys.
We didn't take the low like I wanted to.
Had a pretty pretty not great day of
trading, I suppose. Missed a good short,
got stopped out of a long, never got the
opportunity to take a long
and yeah. So, here we are.
No news, nothing too crazy.
So, what do you guys think? What do you
think? Let's get some music back on. We
need some thinking music.
What do you guys think? Let me know
in the chat.
Jerome answer questions better. Yeah,
seriously, [music]
Trump is live. Is Trump really live or
is he fake live?
Is Trump really live or is he fake live?
Trump live.
No, I don't think he's live.
Is this live?
>> It's impossible to know these days, man.
Trump, man. He he he he definitely looks
a lot older now.
He looks a lot older now.
Wonder why Trump doesn't tweet about the
rate.
Why would he?
Nothing happened. It's not like interest
rates got lower or anything like that.
Make some Beycraft. What is Beycraft?
I don't know what Beycraft is.
What is Beycraft?
Can someone let me know?
Let me try and Google Beycraft.
I just Googled Beycraft.
Let me let me show you what it what came
up here.
What the heck?
This is what I see here.
Beycraft.
This is good old Beep. Good old Bey.
Maybe that will make me feel better. You
know, after a day of losing a little Bey
craft, you know what I'm saying? I'mma
make some bey.
Here we go. Some good old Bey craft.
You can follow Beycraft on Instagram.
What is this?
Here we go. Beycraft.
This is right up my alley.
[laughter]
Yeah, I like this
>> means
[music]
long. [music]
So long.
[music]
>> [singing]
>> along in
cancel. [music]
[singing]
[music]
So long can [music]
so long can
[music]
I
deter [singing]
and sing it. So long he can dancing
[music] his heart. So long he can
dancing.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Can't
[music]
sing.
[music and singing]
>> I'll take some Bey Craft, you know. Good
old Bey, man.
Man.
Sheesh. Crazy.
Um,
what was that actually?
Beycraft.
Well, um, you know what, guys? I'm going
to put together
this this new bench that I got. I got it
on Amazon. I highly recommend it. It's
It's a little bit pricey, but
it's uh Let me show you. Let me show
you. It is the
the Keeppy
the Key 6000 bench. All right, this
thing is is a beauty. All right, the
Keep 6000 bench. It's It's got an
incline bench, got a decline bench. It's
everything you need. Here's here's a
little picture of it. And so far, I've
just got some pieces on the floor. So, I
think I'm going to put that thing
together and I'm going to watch the
chart here. Um,
because if I don't put this bench
together, you know, my stupid self is
going to is going to incline bench press
on my old bench. I almost died doing
that last time. This thing is so wobbly
and old. I got it on Amazon for like I
don't know, like 150 bucks or something
like years ago. This thing's falling
apart.
You can't hear it, but this thing is
wobbly, man. And I almost dropped like a
heavy barbell on my neck the other day
with this thing. So,
you know, God bless you guys.
And uh you can't hear me, huh? That's
weird. Let's see why.
Let's see why you can't hear me.
Usually. Aha. Let's see. Do I have the
convert my Indian accent?
>> Hello everybody. My name is Jason Casper
and I'm here to tell you to buy my
course. All right, I need your money and
I need you to buy my course. So make
sure to click the link in the comment of
the video. Make sure to click the link
in the description of the video and buy
my free course. Everybody, everybody.
Everybody.
How does that sound?
Send array.
Oh, nothing happened. Okay.
Okay. Cool.
Oh, now now you guys hear it.
Hello everybody. My name is Mr. Jason
Casper. I'm here to tell you to buy and
sell Bitcoin. Of course, this is not
financial advice and I'm not a financial
adviser.
I am not a financial adviser. I'm just
Kevin Morris's best friend. Make sure to
wash your hand, everybody. Make sure to
wash your hands. Wash your hands. Wash
your hands. Wash your hands.
Does it sound any different?
Does that sound different or the same?
Okay.
Right.
Yeah. It's not an Indian accent. It's
supposed to filter out my Indian accent.
So, anyway,
peace. Wait a second. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Peace. Peace. Peace. God bless you
guys. Yeah. Tomorrow's Casper Crew Game
Day. Don't forget Don't forget tomorrow
it's Casper Crew Game Day. All right.
Tomorrow's Casper Crew Game Day. The
winner
the winners they get $500. We're going
to be giving away a lot of money. We're
going to be giving away thousands of
dollars, man. Like literally thousands
of dollars. You know what I'm saying?
Thousands. Thousands of dollars.
Thousands of dollars.
This is just a a slow trickle of people
leaving the stream as I announce the end
of the stream like three times here.
Just randomly walking aimlessly in my
basement gym. You know, the good old
Smith machine. You know, this this is a
trusty old Smith machine. I'll tell you
if you guys are in the market for a
Smith machine. I do recommend the Life
Fitness
Smith machine. It's It's actually
Actually, no, that's not true. I'll tell
you guys what I actually recommend. I'll
tell you guys what I actually recommend
right now. All right. Th This This thing
is a game changer. What I'm about to
show you right now is an absolute game
changer. Let me show you.
I just got one of these things.
All right, I just got one of these
things. It's on back order. All right,
it's on back order. I'm waiting for it
to come. This thing here, man. I'm
telling you, don't waste your money if
if you're looking if you're in the
market for a home gym. I'm not even
kidding you. Um,
this this is where it's at. All right.
Now, I know it looks pricey, but you
have to think to yourself, all right, I
have spent honestly I have spent like 30
grand on all this all these like
commercial level machines in this home
gym. This thing here, it does everything
and more and it's only eight grand. It
has a leg press. It's it's it's too good
to be true. I mean, really, but it but
it's true. It's true. Trust me, I've
seen one of these things.
This does everything. All right. It has
a Smith machine. It has a regular bench.
It It has a lat pull down dips. It has
the pull-up bar. It has the functional
trainer with the with the cables. And
the bench itself slides, right? The
bench itself slides. Like, let me let me
see. Look at this. Okay. You could do
like a hack squat with this thing cuz
the bench slides up and down and you
connect it to the cables and you could
do a hack squat with the bench. You
could do a leg press with the bench. You
could do a belt squat.
Let me see. Where's the belt squat? You
know, it's got the landmine, so you can
do this. You could do the hip thrust,
you know, leg extension, leg curl. But
no, you could do you could do everything
on this thing.
Reacher curl, you know, it's it's got it
all, man. I'm telling you. But where?
It's got everything. It's got
everything. It's crazy.
This will save you so much money if if
you're in the market for a home gym.
Look, the leg press, literally like the
bench slides, you got the leg press
machine. It's got 250 lbs on each side
of the dang weight stack, the hack
squat.
Yeah, it's got it all here. I'm telling
you, man.
Smith machine. I love the Smith machine.
Belt squats. Yeah, this. All right. This
is a real game changer. You got yourself
a harness. You hook up your belt to the
dang pulley system. And it's got this
little platform. You can do a dang belt
squat on this, too. Like right now, I
have this belt squat over here. This
thing, the Squat Max MD. I love this
machine. I love it. But imagine if you
could have everything
in the size of a rack. Everything in the
size of one rack. This is the way to go.
I just got myself one of these things
and it's going to be a game changer. I
can't wait for it to come. It's going to
be It's going to be dope. It's going to
be dope. Telling you,
you're in the market for a new
mother-in-law.
Uh I think in order for that to happen,
you need a new wife. All right. So, Fed
basically said they won't do none till
things go down on their own. Everyone's
putting money into the markets anyway.
Never change a running system. Shout out
to Chimp Test. Thank you so much for the
super chat and God bless you.
You know
you don't understand why I tried to mock
the Indian accent. Does anyone think I
tried to mock the Indian accent? Does
anyone actually think that?
Does anyone actually think I tried to
mock the Indian accent?
Who thinks I tried to mock the Indian
accent? Let me know.
Yeah, this thing is cheap, guys. I'm
telling you, this thing is cheap.
The machine's not that user friendly.
Well, here's the thing. Obviously, if
you're going to set up like if you're
going to go from like a Smith machine
press to like a a leg press, yeah,
that's going to take mad time. That's
going to take mad time. So, the way you
have to do it is you have to plan your
workout. You have to plan it in the in
the right order. But, if you're if
you're in the market for a home gym, you
want to save space and money. I mean,
this thing to me is a no-brainer. And
besides,
maybe that maybe that longer rest period
in between will help you hit a new PR.
You know what I mean?
You know what I'm saying? Yeah, belt
squats are epic. I I love belt squats
because I'm tall and I love back squats,
don't get me wrong. I love them, but
they really I they don't really work my
legs too much. Not like a belt squat.
It took me so much time to get my squat
form good. took me such a long time to
be able to really squat to depth with
weight and after all that squatting.
Obviously, my legs are skinny. You guys
who know know, but my quads did not grow
very much from squatting heavy with a
barbell as much as they did from the
belt squat.
Shout out to Minepillar Markets. Good to
see you here, man. Guys, make sure to go
subscribe to Minepillar Markets. All
right, Andy and the other guy whose name
I can't remember,
but
formerly Andy from Bitcoin Census and
now Andy from Mindpillar Markets.
He's getting the Flash F90. Yeah, I I
got one. It's on back order. It should
be It should ship next month. So, we'll
see. We'll see.
We'll see. I'm not putting it I'm not
putting it in this gym. I'm putting it
in a different gym.
This gym is is set in stone there.
There's nothing more I can add to this
gym. Although
I did almost buy I did almost buy more
gym equipment. And then I realized I
shouldn't buy more gym equipment cuz you
know then I have to explain to my wife
why I need more gym equipment. I'm just
not in the mood to have that
conversation today. But maybe tomorrow
I'll buy something. I do have this
thing. You know what? I haven't put this
together yet. I don't even know what
this is. I don't actually don't even
know what this is. What is this thing?
It's a Titan. It's a Titan fitness
thing.
I have no idea what it even is. See if I
can if it says somewhere.
Doesn't say.
So, I've had it for a long time and I
guess it doesn't say. And I'm scared to
open it because if I do, I find out what
it is now, it's out of the box. If I
don't want to put it together, it's
stuck out of the box. I wish I knew what
this thing was. It You know what? It
might be something that I really want.
Maybe it's like a glute hand raise
machine.
You know, I don't know what this thing
is.
I don't I should open it. You know what?
You guys have inspired me to open it.
You know, it's definitely not a
treadmill.
This is a good question. Why Why do I
buy brand new fitness equipment when you
can get it used on the dollar? Here's
why. So, I've had a home gym now since
2018,
and I've spent a lot of money on crappy
fitness equipment. All right? I've spent
a lot of money on really bad fitness
equipment. Now, the only things I would
buy used would be things like weight
plates, barbells, dumbbells. If you're
trying to have like some kind of a or or
like an old rack, okay? Or or an old
rack. But if you're trying to have
something nice like a fly machine or a
leg press machine or a cable machine
like a lap pull down machine, you need
to buy high-end stuff. All right? If
[snorts] you're trying to buy used
stuff, you're going to run into issues
with it. First of all, it's hard to find
quality used stuff. And if you can find
it, there there there can be issues with
it. And I I wasted a lot of money buying
used and cheap equipment.
And then one day I realized, you know
what? Why not just buy it new?
Then I won't have to deal with all those
issues. That's why I buy new stuff. You
know what I'm saying? A chicken plucking
machine. I actually have one of those. I
have a chicken plucking machine. Here,
I'll show you guys my chicken plucker.
Let's check out the chicken plucker.
Ah, here it is. The good old chicken
plucker.
Yeah, the good old chicken plucker. Here
she is.
There's the chicken plucker.
Yep. You just put the old chicken in
here.
Look, there's still got some old
feathers in there, too. See those old
feathers in there? And actually, here's
the here's some old garlic, too. This is
old garlic from 2025.
Still smells great.
I'm actually going to plant that garlic
this coming year.
Yeah, the old chicken plucker machine.
All right, I'll take a picture of the
box and ask AI what this thing is. AI
won't know. There's no way AI will know.
AI is not that smart.
Yeah, but good thinking. Good thinking.
Ask good old chat GPT.
Good old chat GPT.
What is this?
Let's see what chat GBT says.
It's a large cardboard box with Titan
Fitness on it.
It doesn't know. It has no idea.
It has no idea.
If you're actually asking about what's
inside the boxes, I can't determine that
from the exterior alone because the
packaging is generic Titan Fitness
branding.
It doesn't have a shipping label or a
model number on it. Not that I could
tell.
Do they sell weights a dollar per pound?
I actually have no idea. I have no idea.
A lot of my weights I did get for free.
Like this I got for free.
This is uh
some old stuff I got from a friend
years ago.
Let's see here. Let me see. Maybe it's
on the other side of the box.
Oh, wait. There's something up here.
Name plate loaded fly machine.
It's a plateloaded fly machine.
Maybe I'll maybe I'll maybe I'll unwrap
it. You know, I do have I do have um I
do have, you know, I've got the cable
functional trainer over here and I've
got the Life Fitness the uh you know,
the good old your your standard your
standard uh whatchamacall machine. You
know, this this guy.
Well, they